A Guide to the Photographic Negatives of Richard N. Anderson,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Richmond, Virginia. Government Office Buildings, n. d., 31 images, 8 negatives. (Box-folder 1:42)
  2 images of a [Negro family leaving the Richmond Post Office] #1460 D.1-2; 16 images of the United States Post Office Westhampton [1950] #1460 N.1-16; 3 images of the National Guard Armory and the Federal Office Building n.d. #1527 A-C; 4 images of the Governor's mansion #1784 J-M; 4 negatives of the Governor's mansion #1784 J-M; 1 image of the Richmond City Hall Building # 1784 R; 1 image of the Richmond Federal Building #1784 S; 4 images of downtown Richmond #1784; 4 negatives of panoramic Richmond including City Hall and the Richmond Federal Building #1784 N-S; 4 negatives of the Richmond State Capitol #1784 T-W.
- Richmond, Virginia, Residences, n. d., 69 images and 4 photographs. (Box-folder 1:43)
  28 images of residences, Bransford-Cecil House #1501 A-X relocated from 5th and Franklin Streets to East Clay Street to become the Valentine Museum #1534 C-D; Wright Residence #1534 A-B; 2 photographs and 4 images of residences, Crozet House, First and East Main Streets [1950] #1533 A, #1533 B-E, #1460 Y; 1 photograph and 4 images of [Grandis Residence] and shops in the Bellevue neighborhood #1460 AC, #1534 E-H; 2 images of Hanover Arms Apartments #1460 Z.1-2; 1 photograph of the [Stewart-Lee House] #1460 AE; 2 images of the Hillside Court, RRHA Public Housing Project [1950] #1460 W.1-2; 2 images of the Carrington residence [1950] #1460 X.1-2; 3 images of the Boxley residence [1951] #1460 AA.1-3; 4 images of the Tempsford Lane residence [1957] #1460 AB1-4; 20 images of the "slums" in the Jackson Ward area and the public housing [Gilpin Court] that replaced them [1950] 1500 A-T.
- Richmond, Virginia Schools and Parks including the Carillon, Parade [1942], and War Memorial, n. d., 33 images, 2 photographs, 1 negative. (Box-folder 1:44)
  2 images of the Memorial Carillon, Byrd Park #1522 A-B; 3 images of the James River at Mayo's Island when minor league baseball field and the Virginia Boat Club were located there #1518 A-C; 6 images and 1 photograph of the World War II Recruitment and Parade 1942 #1536, #1535 A-F; 2 images of a parakeet named Beauregard and Mrs. Shuford 1958 October #1539 A-B; #1500A-T; 1 photograph of Blackwell School #1524; 12 images of the Richmond Virginia Jewish Center #1509 A-L; 8 images of the Virginia War Memorial n.d. #1460 R.1-8; 1 negative of Shockhoe Valley #1786.
- Richmond, Virginia and other places, [1950's], n. d., 9 images, 2 photographs. (Box-folder 1:45)
  1 photograph of buildings in San Francisco, California (1944) #1460 AZ; 4 images of Adair & Hutton Inc. Lexington, Virginia and Amderton's Department Store, Tappahannock, Virginia [1950's] #1460 AT.1-2, AU.1-2; 2 images of J. Henley Walker Paper Company Building (1952) #1460 O.1-2; 1 photograph of a bomb scare at Trailways Bus Depot (1958 October) #1460 AN; 3 images of a sheriff with a murderer at Division 1 State Police Headquarters and a young unidentified woman in the waiting area (1958 Nov) #1460 AQ1-3.
- Bill Bojangles Robinson arriving at Broad Street Station, Richmond, Virginia, [1940], 2 photographs. (Box-folder 1:46)
  #1431, #1540.
- Franklin Delano Roosevelt with General Edwin Watson and his wife, [1940], 1 photograph. (Box-folder 1:47)
  #1460 BB.
- Space Radiation Effects Laboratory, Hampton, Virginia [1964]; residential fire n.d.; Joint Faith Service 1961 October, n. d., 31 images. (Box-folder 1:48)
  29 images of the Space Radiation Effects Laboratory [1964] #35-200 DI-DJ, #35-201 H-J; 3 images of a residential fire #35-200 DL; 2 images of a Joint Faith Service at the John Marshall Hotel 1961 Oct. 1 #35-200 DK.
- Charlie Spivak and his orchestra, n. d., 3 photographs. (Box-folder 1:48)
- Herman Talmadge, and three unidentified men at the Virginia War Memorial, [1957] April 29, 1 image. (Box-folder 1:49)
  #1126.
- Train Stations, Train Derailment and NASA Lunar Landing Simulator; Chemical Company, [1950]; 1964 May 26, n. d., 26 images. (Box-folder 1:50)
  4 images of Rear Main Street Station, Richmond, Virginia [1950] #35-201 D; 6 images of Rear Broad Street Station, Richmond, Virginia [1960] #35-201 E; 5 images of NASA Lunar Landing Simulator, Langley Air Force Base 1964 May 26 #35-201 F; 3 images of a train derailment #35-201 A; 4 images of the Virginia-Carolina Chemical Company, Richmond, Virginia #35-201 B; 4 images of Rear of Union Station, Washington, D. C. 1950 #35-201C.
- Hore Browse Trist, Photograph of a St. Memin engraving of Hore Browse Trist, n. d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:51)
- University of Richmond Homecoming Queen, [Miss Virginia Beauty Pageant], n. d., 15 images, 2 photographs. (Box-folder 2:1)
  1 photograph of the University of Richmond Homecoming Queen #1460 AL; 15 images and 1 photograph of the Miss Virginia Beauty Pageant and Miss Virginia 1948 #1538A-K; 1958 September 7 1460 BA.1-5.
- University of Virginia, n. d., 1 photograph, 1 negative #1784 X, 1 illustration, 1 photocopy. (Box-folder 2:2)
  1 photograph of a garden on the Lawn, 1 illustration of an unidentified house, 1 photocopy of the UVA ampitheatre.
- USS Loesser in Richmond, Virginia; n.d.; USS Savannah and Coast Guard Training Ship Eagle at Yorktown, 1962 August 17, 16 images. (Box-folder 2:3)
  4 images of the USS Loesser #35-201 O; 12 images of the USS Savannah and Eagle #35-201 M-N.
- George C. Wallace on a presidential campaign trip to Richmond, 1964 June 27, 33 images. (Box-folder 2:4)
  #35-200 BL-BR.
- Williamsburg, Virginia. Buildings, n. d., 6 images, 1 photograph. (Box-folder 2:5)
  1 photograph of a [College] building #1534 I; 1 image of an unidentified building in front of the train track #1133A; 1 image of the Williamsburg Courthouse #1133 B; 3 images of the Governor's Palace #1133 C-E;1 image of the Williamsburg Capitol Building #1133 F.
- Williamsburg, Virginia. Movie filming [1939] and 4th of July Speakers on the steps of the Virginia Capitol Hill, [1941], 9 images, 1 photograph. (Box-folder 2:6)
  1 photograph of a film being shot in Colonial Williamsburg #1460 AS; 9 images of a film being shot in Colonial Williamsburg #1430 A-D, #1537 A-C; 2 images of 4th of July speakers on Virginia Capitol Steps #1460 AR.1-2.
- Wingless Wonder airplane, n. d., 1 image. (Box-folder 2:7)
- WRVA Primary election coverage 1960, 1965; Clarence Townes; Senator A. Willis Robertson, n. d., 66 images, 1 photograph, 11 photocopies. (Box-folder 2:8)
  1 photograph of WRVA on Broad Street #1531 A; 2 images of Senator Willis Robertson #35-200 AU; 64 images of the WRVA Primary Election Coverage 1965 July #35-200 AV-AW; 1958 September. #1531 B-C; 11 images (photocopy) of Clarence Townes #35-200 AS-AT.